PHANI KUMAR KOLLA

Hyderabad, Telangana, India



pkkolla24@gmail.com



9052436874



linkedin.com/in/phanikumarkolla

Summary

I am a passionate coder, a thorough troubleshooter, a problem solver and an enthusiastic lead developer. A Professional Cloud Architect and Technology Lead with 12 years of experience in the areas of Product Development and Design, Web Services and API design & Implementation.

Experience

wf Vice President

Wells Fargo

Feb 2022 - Present (11 months +)

- o Built new micro services / decomposing monolith applications into microservices.
- o Cracked Google Cloud Professional Architecture Certification and Professional Machine Learning Engineer is in Process
- o Handling 4 teams in terms of technical guidance and leadership
- o Training team members on Cloud services
- o Migration of applications from AXIS 1.X to Spring Web Services & APIGEE Marketplace
- o Driving the Server migration from WebSphere to Tomcat which involves the Stress/Load Testing
- o Implementation of EPL pipeline which involves Jenkins & uDeploy for the Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery

WF Assistant Vice President

Wells Fargo

Sep 2020 - Feb 2022 (1 year 6 months)

- o Successfully delivered the rewritten 2 applications to production in phase wise rollout manner.
- o Improved the screen rendering post login with high performance and responsiveness to the end users
- o Line Of Business was very happy with the delivered product with high performance
- o Implemented a Chat bot for the LOB user which is available 24*7
- o Implemented a Machine Learning Model to provide the credit recommendation for the customer based on the customer credit history
- o API development and code review to optimize for better efficiency in terms of time complexity

wf Senior Technology Specialist

Wells Fargo

Jun 2017 - Sep 2020 (3 years 4 months)

Technology Lead for DAT application

- o Lead a team of 8 with 6 senior analysts.
- o Lead the engineering team in planning for and delivering all product release efforts including major releases, minor releases, and patches
- o High level designing and low level designing for the rewrite of the application
- o Application rewrite from Java Applets to Spring Boot.

- o Created monitoring dashboards from SPLUNK and APPD data.
- o Worked as a Business Resiliency Coordinator for the application which helps in disaster recovery.

WF Technology Specialist

Wells Fargo

Sep 2015 - May 2017 (1 year 9 months)

Key Contributions:

- o 3 new batch jobs development and successful deployment to Production
- o Migration of Ant build to Gradle build for both the applications
- o Application scan through Fortify tool and fixing the vulnerabilities identified through scans

WF Senior Analyst

Wells Fargo

Dec 2013 - Aug 2015 (1 year 9 months)

- o Involved in development of batch jobs and services for the Standalone batch environment.
- o Worked on enhancements on the web application, which was developed on Java Applets, JSP and EJB's.
- o Production support activities which involve monitoring the application and debugging the issues in production.

Software Engineer

E2open

Oct 2011 - Nov 2013 (2 years 2 months)

- o Interact with Client, Coding for Controller, business logic, parsing XML Data, generating PDF, CSV and Excel, java mail service.
- o UML design and Unit Test cases, Designing Web Pages, Request Processor, Validations, Code Integrations using Win-CVS
- o Preparing Technical Design Documents as per release.

Education



Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University

B.Tech, Computer Science and Engineering 2007 - 2011



Gowtham Junior College

Board Of Intermediate, M P C 2005 - 2007



Srinivasa Public School

Secondary School Certification, SSC

1995 - 2005

A casual sportsman & an athlete.

Licenses & Certifications

- Oracle Certified Projessional Java Programmer SE 1.6 Oracle 1Z0-851
- 1Z0-899 Java Platform, EE 6 Web Component Developer Certified Expert Oracle 1Z0-899
- Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Architect Google Issued Jul 2022 - Expires Jul 2024 1pfpU5
- in Java 8 for Professionals LinkedIn

Skills

Microservices • Spring Boot • React.js • Apache Kafka • RESTful WebServices • SOAP • Google Cloud Platform (GCP) • Solution Architecture • Java • Machine Learning